Guide to the Records of the Office of Senior Vice President for Administration 1981-1983 ACC 84.008 RG 8.0.3
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of Senior Vice President for Administration
1981-1983
RG 8.0.3
New York University Archives
8.0 linear feet 8 linear feet (8 boxes)
The Senior Vice President for Administration is chiefly responsibility for non-academic affairs, finances and physical plant. William Vandament held the post from November of 1981 through May of 1983 under President John Brademas. The collection contains records of the office from Vandament's term and includes various financial and administrative records, and correspondence.
New York University. Office of Senior Vice President for Administration.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into series:
Inventory.
Physical Access
Please note that this collection is stored offsite, and you must contact the repository to schedule access.
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains records from the Office of Senior Vice President for Administration during William Vandament's term and includes various financial and administrative records, and correspondence.
Records include files arranged by topic in one series. Folders, though mostly undated, fall within the years: 1981-1983, and include information on: academic computer facilities, expenditure control reports, admissions, applicants for positions, Associations of Colleges and Universities of New York, the 1981 Audit, budget guidelines, the Computer Center, salaries, candidates for positions, and the Center for Scientific & Technological Policy (GBA).
Historical/Biographical Note
The Senior Vice President for Administration is the third highest office in the university's administration. The office's chief responsibility is for non-academic affairs, finances and physical plant. William Vandament, formerly Vice President for Finance and Planning at Ohio State University, held the post from November of 1981 through May of 1983 under President John Brademas.
Vandament earned a Ph.D. in psychology from the University of Massachusetts in 1964 and taught at SUNY Binghamton from 1964-1969; after which, his career turned to university administration.
In his time as Senior Vice President for Administration, Vandament focused on resolving financial problems at the College of Dentistry where he successfully lobbied for significant State support. Vandament was also active in upgrading of the university's computer facilities.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
This collection is in
off-site storage
Provenance
Brademas, John, 1927-; New York University. History. 20th century.; New York University.; Vandament, William E.; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Private universities and colleges |x Administration |y 20th century.; Universities and colleges |x Finance.
- Inventory
  - Academic Affairs, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    3 1142 04225105 1
  - Academic Computer Facilities, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accounting System, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administration, Office of Administrative Management Council (AMC):, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Credit Union, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Expenditure Control Reports, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Admissions, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Federation, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Foundation, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Applicants for Positions, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Associations of Colleges and Universities of New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Association of Institutional Research, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Audit: 1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Benefits, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brademas's Friends, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget Compensation, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Budget Guidelines Budget, 1982-83:, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Administrative Incremental Requisitions, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Administrative Offices, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Administrative Retrenchment, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Administrative Services, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Computer Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Finance, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Fringe Benefits, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Institutional Facilities, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Personnel, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Salaries, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Schools/Colleges, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Budget Meetings, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Barney Building, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - White Building, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Candidates for Position, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Catering, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Center for Scientific & Technological Policy (GBA), undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Citibank, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Cogeneration Project, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Coles Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Commencement, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Community Relations, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Complaints, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Compensation: Benefits, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Computer Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cost Allocation Formula, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Science, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Creative Arts Team, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Credit Union, Councils/Commissions/Committees, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Faculty Council (A+B), undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Student Senators Council, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Senate Financial Affairs Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - University Committee on Student Life, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - University Senate, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Trustees Investment Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Trustee Budget Subcommittee, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1981 Nov - 1981 Dec (Box 2, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225106 9
  - Correspondence, 1982 Jan - 1982 Aug (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Day-to-Day Memoranda, 1982 Dec - 1983 Aug (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Development Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Donors, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dormitory Authority, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dental Center: Administrative Task Force, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dental Center: Board of Regents, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dental Center: Board of Regents, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dental Center: Board of Regents, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dental Center: Comparative Data, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dental Center: Contingency Plans, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dental Center: Contract Proposals, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dental Center: Division of the Budget, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dental Center: External Relations, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dental Center: Facilities Study, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dental Center: General, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dental Center: Legal Issues, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dental Center: Emergencies, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dental Center: Employment, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dental Center: Endowment, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Dental Center: Energy Conservation, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Dental Center: Enrollment, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Dental Center: Ernst + Whinney, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Dental Center: Facilities Office, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Dental Center: Facilities Planning and Management, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dental Center: Faculty Benefits Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Dental Center: Faculty Salaries, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Dental Center: Faculty Staff Housing, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Faculty Staff Meetings: Dental School, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Faculty Staff Meetings: School of Business, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Faculty Staff Meetings: GPA, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Faculty Staff Meetings: Arts + Science, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Faculty Staff Meetings: Courant, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Federal Relations, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - FERPA (Federal Education Rights + Privacy Act 1974), undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Finance Office - Balance Sheet, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Financial Aid, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Food Service Management, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Fringe Benefits, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - GBA Library, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225107 7
  - Government Relations, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Grey Art Gallery, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Higher Education and National Affairs, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Housing Task Force, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Humanities Council, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Institute for Cultural Analysis, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Institutional Facilities, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Institute of Fine Arts, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Institution Work Plan, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - International Programs, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Law Center: Faciltites, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Law Center: Foundation, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Law Center: Library, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Law Center: Listening Post, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Medical Center, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Medical Center: Central Admissions, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Meetings: Deans, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Meetings: 5-Way, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Meetings: President's Speech Schedule, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Meetings: Staff Meetings, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Meetings: University Senate Meeting, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Meetings: VP Meetings, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - New York Congressmen, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Office of Senior VP: ECR's, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Payroll, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Personnel Services, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Provost's Office, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Purchasing Division, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Salary Review Committee, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Security, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Shea, Doreen - Salary Report, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Sponsored Programs, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Staffing Report, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - State Dormitory Authority, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - State of New York: Executive Budget, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - State Relations, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Student Affairs, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Student Information Systems (SIS): Project Team, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Student Information Systems (SIS): Users Group, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Student Information Systems (SIS): General, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Staff Negotiations, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Student Housing, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - WSUC, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225108 5
  - School of Law, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - School of Medicine, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - College of Dentistry, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - GSAS, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - SEHNAP, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - BPA, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - GBA, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - SCE, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - GPA, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Post Graduate Medicine, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - School of Social Work, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - School of the Arts, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Telecommunications, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Time Modules, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Treasurer's Office, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Tuition, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Telephone Bills, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Telephone Reps, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Travel Advance Requests, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Travel Expense Vouchers, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Undergraduate Deans, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - United Way Campaign, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - University - Industry Cooperation, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Vacation, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Vandament - Salary Report, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Washington Square Park, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Pending, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Purchase Requisitions, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Requests for Checks, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Receipts - Calendar, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Board of Trustees: Investments Subcommittee, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Board of Trustees, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Executive Committee, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Financial Affairs, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225109 3
  - Committee on Trustees, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Academic Affairs Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Student Affairs Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Development Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Audit Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Computer Center, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Security, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Student Housing, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Formation Report, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Deans, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Peat/ Marwick, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Computer Center, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Project Team, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Student Information System (SIS): I. D. Center, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Users Group, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Law School, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Student Information System (SIS): Assorted, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Westinghouse, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225110 1
  - Medical Center Files, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Administration, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Admissions, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ancillary Project, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ancillary Service Project, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Benefits, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - MC Budget 1981-82, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1982-83, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - MC Budget + Financial, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - MC Capital Budget, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - MC Capital Projects, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cooper Lybrand Study, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Dermatology Project, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Development, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Energy Projects (1,2), undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Financial Information System, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Financial Issues, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Financial Statements (1), undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Financial Statements (2), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225111 9
  - MC General, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - MC Housing, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - MC Long Range Plans, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - MC Foundation, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - New York Office of Health Systems Mgmt (OHSM), undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Practical Plan, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Press Issues, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reimbursement Study, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Medical Center Board (1,2), undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Medical Center Board: Executive Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Medical Center Board: Financial + Budget Committee (1,2), undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Medical Center Board: Telecommunications Studies, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - UNFILED/ UNCLASSIFIED materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - UNFILED/ UNCLASSIFIED materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - UNFILED/ UNCLASSIFIED materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - UNFILED/ UNCLASSIFIED materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - SIS Reports (Numerous copies), undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225112 7